A mother. A daughter. Three possible fathers. A trip
down the aisle you'll never forget.
Mamma Mia! is a comedy, romance film directed by Phyllida Lloyd.
A spirited young bride-to-be living with her single mother on a small Greek island secretly invites three of
her mother's ex-boyfriends in hope of finding her biological father to walk her down the aisle.
Donna Sheridan, played by Meryl Streep.
Sophie Sheridan, played by Amanda Seyfried.
Sam Carmichael, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Harry Bright, played by Colin Firth.
Bill Anderson, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Rosie Mulligan, played by Julie Walters.
(promoted as Mamma Mia!
The Movie) is a 2008 jukebox musical romantic comedy film directed by Phyllida Lloyd and written
by Catherine Johnson, based on her book from the 1999 musical of the same name.
The film features an ensemble cast, including Meryl Streep, Pierce Brosnan, Colin Firth, Stellan
Skarsgård, Julie Walters, Dominic Cooper, Amanda Seyfried, and Christine Baranski.
The film follows a young bride-to-be named Sophie who invites three men to her upcoming
wedding, with the possibility that any of them could be her real father.
Principal photography primarily took place on the island of Skopelos, Greece, from August to September
2007, with ABBA members Benny Andersson and Björn Ulvaeus composing the film's score.
premiered at the Leicester Square in London on June 30, 2008, before being released in the United
Kingdom on July 10, and in the United States on July 18, by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office success, grossing $610 million
worldwide on a $52 million budget, becoming the fifth highest-grossing film of 2008.
A sequel, titled Mamma Mia!
Here We Go Again, was released on July 20, 2018,
with much of the cast returning.
The film explores themes of single parent, parent child
relationship, greece, musical, romcom.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.